pot-holing: n.   洞穴探险，洞穴探险运动
Lesson 42. Modern cavemen. Cave exploration. Or pot-holing. As it has come to be known.
第42课。现代穴居人。洞穴探索。或锅里。众所周知。
solitude: n.   孤独，寂寞
Is a relatively new sport. Perhaps it is the desire for solitude or the chance of making an
是一项相对较新的运动。也许这是孤独的渴望或
lure: v.   引诱，诱惑
unexpected discovery that lures. People down to the depths of the earth. It is impossible to give a
意外的发现引诱。人们走到地球的深处。不可能给
pot-holer: n.   洞穴探险者
satisfactory explanation for a pot-holer's motives. For him, caves have the same peculiar fascination
令人满意的解释锅孔的动机。对他来说，洞穴具有相同的奇特迷恋
which high mountains have for the climber. They arouse instincts which can only be dimly understood.
高山为登山者提供。它们引起了只能被昏迷的本能。
undertaking: n.   任务，工作
Exploring really deep caves is not a task for the Sunday afternoon rambler. Such undertakings require
对于周日下午的漫步者来说，探索真正的洞穴并不是一项任务。这样的事业需要
foresight: n.   预见；深谋远虑
the precise planning and foresight of military operations. It can take as long as eight days to
军事行动的确切计划和远见。可能需要长达八天的时间
rig up rope ladders and to establish supply bases before a. Descent can be made into a very deep cave.
在绳索梯子上设置绳索，并在a之前建立供应基地。下降可以将其制成一个非常深的洞穴。
foretell: v.   预言
Procautions of this sort are necessary. For it is impossible to foretell the exact nature of the
这种预防措施是必要的。因为不可能预言
pot-holer: n.   洞穴探险者
difficulties which will confront the pot-holer. The deepest known cave in the world is the
会遇到锅炉的困难。世界上最深的洞穴是
Grenoble: n.   格里诺布尔, chasm: n.   断层，裂口，陷坑
Goofrey burger near Grenoble. It extends to a depth of 3,723 feet. This immense chasm has been
Goofrey Burger附近的Grenoble。它延伸到3,723英尺的深度。这种巨大的鸿沟已经
formed by an underground stream which has tunneled a course through a. Flaw in the rocks. The entrance
由地下溪流形成，该溪流通过A隧道道上的隧道形成。岩石中的缺陷。入口
to the cave is on a plateau in the Daffine Alps. As it is only six feet across, it is barely noticeable.
山洞位于水仙阿尔卑斯山的高原上。由于它只有六英尺，因此几乎没有明显。
distinguished: adj. 杰出的，著名的
The cave might never have been discovered has not the entrance been spotted by the distinguished.
洞穴可能从未被发现，没有被杰出的入口发现。
pot-holer: n.   洞穴探险者, Everest: n.   珠穆朗玛峰
French pot-holer burger. Since its discovery, it has become a sort of pot-holer's Everest,
法国锅汉堡。自发现以来，它已成为一种陶罐的珠穆朗玛峰，
pot-holer: n.   洞穴探险者
though a number of descents have been made. Much of it still remains to be explored. A team of pot-holers
尽管已经下降了。其中的大部分仍然有待探索。一支锅炉团队
recently went down the Goofrey burger. After entering the narrow gap on the plateau, they climbed
最近掉下了Goofrey汉堡。进入高原上的狭窄缝隙后，他们爬了
down the steep sides of the cave until they came to narrow corridor. They had to edge their way
沿着山洞的陡峭侧面，直到走向狭窄的走廊。他们不得不前进
along this. Sometimes waiting across shallow streams or swimming across deep pools. Suddenly they
沿着这个。有时在浅水中等待或在深水游泳池中游泳。突然他们
waterfall: n.   瀑布
came to a waterfall which dropped into an underground lake at the bottom of the cave. They plunged
来到一个瀑布，落入了洞穴底部的地下湖中。他们跌倒了
gear: n.   一套用具, inflatable: adj. 可充气的
into the lake. And after loading their gear on an inflatable rubber dinghy, let the current carry
进入湖。然后将齿轮装在充气橡胶小艇上，让电流携带
them to the other side. To protect themselves from the icy water, they had to wear special rubber
他们到另一边。为了保护自己免受冰冷的水，他们必须穿特殊的橡胶
rubble: n.   碎瓦
suits. At the far end of the lake, they came to huge piles of rubble which had been washed up by the
西装。在湖的远端，他们来到了大堆废墟
insistent: adj. 连续的，不断的, boom: v.   轰响
water. In this part of the cave, they could hear an insistent booming sound which they found was
水。在洞穴的这一部分，他们可以听到他们发现的坚持蓬勃的声音
caused by a small water spout. Shooting down into a pool from the roof of the cave, squeezing
由小水口引起。从洞穴的屋顶上射入游泳池，挤压
pot-holer: n.   洞穴探险者, cleft: n.   裂隙，开, cavern: n.   在洞穴
through a cleft in the rocks. The pot-holers arrived at an enormous cavern. The size of a huge concert hall.
穿过岩石中的裂缝。储池到达了一个巨大的洞穴。大型音乐厅的大小。
stalagmite: n.   石笋
After switching on powerful arc lights, they saw great stalagmites, some of them over 40 feet high,
打开强大的弧光后，他们看到了伟大的石灰石，其中一些高40英尺高，
stalactite: n.   钟乳石
rising up like tree trunks to. Meet the stalactites suspended from the roof. Round about,
像树干一样上升。遇到悬挂在屋顶的钟乳石。四处走动，
cavern: n.   在洞穴, limestone: n.   石灰石, glisten: v.   闪烁
piles of limestone glistened in all the colors of the rainbow. In the eerie silence of the cavern,
彩虹的所有颜色都闪闪发光。在洞穴的令人毛骨悚然的沉默中
dome: n.   穹窿，圆顶
the only sound that could be heard was made by water which dripped continuously from the high dome.
唯一可以听到的声音是通过从高圆顶连续滴落的水发出的。
Above them,
在他们上方，